Inventory of the United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1941-1946
  - American correspondent reports, 1941-1946
    - Waverly Edwards radio report, 1945 April (Record cabinet)
      Edwards reports from Guam on the battle over Okinawa from his first-hand experience accompanying the American forces.
  - Miscellaneous recordings, 1941-1946
    - A Plea to Mothers, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Frederick Kister asks mothers of the country to remember the first world war and join in a crusade against the United States entering World War II.
    - Audio reportage of Harold Smith to the Chicago Tribune via the Mutual Broadcasting System, 194? October 28 (Record cabinet)
      The first story concerns the experiences of the American soldier following the battle of the Philippines.
      The second story concerns Filipino guerrilla fighters actions against the Japanese.
    - Christmas and New Years radio show, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      This recording is a Christmas and New Years program featuring the Triton chorus.
    - Coded signal radio transmissions, 1942 February 18 (Record cabinet)
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      2A: Japanese Conversation Drill, J5.31 - Repeated - different voices
      2B: Japanese Conversation Drill, J7.23, J7.24, J7/24 Conv 3, J8.21 Conv 1.
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 3A - J8.21, J9.22 Conv 1, J9.22 Conv 2
      Side B: 3B - J10.25, J10.25 Con 2, J11.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Jarrett, Jarman, Julliuson, 5A, Unit III
      Side B: Jarrett, Jarman, Julliuson, 5B, Unit III
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Eastman Reynolds 31A Unit
      Side B: Reynolds Eastman 31B Unit IV
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A - Marshall, Gunston - 24A, Unit I
      Side B -
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1945 April 30 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Braden, Britt - 4A Unit II
      Side B: Abbett, Bonnett - 4B Unit III - 30 Apr 1945
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 1B - J.1.24, J.1.25, J.2.21
      Side B: 1B - J2.22, J3.20, J3.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 2A - J.4.16, J.5.31
      Side B: 2B - J.5.31
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 1A - J.1.24; J1.25; J.2.21; J2.22
      Side B: 1B - J3.20; J3.21; J4.16
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 13A - J3.20, changing voices: GH Goody, PH Walker, JD Kriel
      Side B: #13B - J3.21, HT Grant, CE Gustof, PH Walker; J3.20 Grant, Gustafogu, Walker, and Driel
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 21A Unit IV - Gashins, Hope
      Side B: 21B Unit IV - Auburn, Adams
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1946 July (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 1A - Hess, Goldman
      Side B: 1b - Hess, Goldman - 7-46
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Lieut. Beattie, Capt. Abbott, Lieut. Borwich
      Side A: 11A
      Side B: 11B
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Platkins, Linthicum - Unit I
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 20A - Wyman+Ward, 8.21-8.22
      Side B: 20B - Ward-Wyman, 8.21-8.22
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 22A - Justice, Wells, Bilcovitch
      Side B: 22B - Wells, Bilcovitch, Bergeson, Eastley
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 10A - J4.16 - Maj. Bardin, Maj. Henderson, Lt. Comlk McClellan
      Side B: 10B - J4.16 - Bardin, Anderson - 7.23 Conv1 Bardin, Maj. Anderson - 7.24 Conv 2 McClellan, Anderson - 7.24 Conv 3 McClellan, Anderson
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      16A - J7.23 - conv 1 - Hansen, Williams
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: IA - J1.24, J1.25, J2.21, J2.22
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 15 - Adachi, Inouye, and Masuyama
      Side B: 16 - Masuyama, Inouye, Adachi
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: IIIA - J.8.21 Con 2, J9.22 Con 2, J9.22 Con 2
      Side B: IIIB - J10.25 Con 1, J10.25 Con 2, J11.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Capt John H Ford, Capt F C Pollard
      Side A: #2A - J1.24, J1.25 changing voices
      Side B: #2B - J2.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A has no label information
      Side B: #1B - J3.20, J3.21, J4.16
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Number 5 Wallace Pnettie, 14A Unit I
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Faulkner, Curron - 22A(b) Unit III
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 12A - 2.21 Bergeson, Gaumond; 2.22 Larson, Hasenyager
      Side B: 2.21 Larson, Hasenyager; 2.21 Larson, Hasenyager, Bergeson
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Number 7A - J.3.20, J.3.21 K.U. Mason; Preston Halder; M.M. Halwer
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: IIA - J5.31, change of voices
      Side B: IIB - J7.23, J2.24 Conv 1, J7.24 Conv 2, J8.21 Con 1
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      1A, 1B - J1.24, J1.25, J2.21 - E Johnson and JL Kiraley
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Lacke, Koidal - 7A Unit IV, 7B Unit IV
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Prettie, Reed - 12A Unit I
      Side B: Redfield, Milniore - 12B, Unit I
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      9A Unit II, 9B Unit II
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Eastman, Rees - 32A Unit IV, 32B Unit IV
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Jeskovik, Kirby 26A Unit V
      Side B: Mould, Gunston 26B Unit V
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1945 April 30 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Austin-Austin 3A, Unit II
      Side B: Alexander-Ballentine 3B, Unit II
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Grope 3, #1-3
      Padulla, Lutz, Malcolm
      20A Unit III, 20B Unit III
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 9A - J5.31 - Lt. Mac Innis, Capt. Moring, Fager, Lyons
      Side B: 9B - J5.31 - Fager, Lyons, Pilkington, Morris
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Yu, Heyl - 29A Unit IV, 29B Unit IV
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 4A - J4.16 - Sobel, Phillipi, Alcock
      Side B: 4B - J3.20 - Sobel, RB Johnson, Alcock
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Knudseuz Dyea
      Side A: 11A, Unit II
      Side B: 11B, Unit II
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 2A: J5.31 - repeated, different voices
      Side B: 2B: J7.23, J7.24 conv, J.724 Conv 3, J8.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1944 November 1 (Record cabinet)
      8A: Cpl Morehouse, Rt Farr J4.16, Rt King - diauguis voices
      8B: J4.16 - Morehouse, Farr, and King
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Freeluesu Elishoudt, 15A Unit II
      Side B: Eaeduz Harland, 15B Unit II
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Liabrest Heahtea, 22A(a) Unit IV
      Side B: Leadeu Naulkues, 22B(a) Unit IV
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: #2A J5.31, J5.31, 7.231
      Side B: #2B J7.23, J7.24(1), J7.24(2), J8.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 21A Wells, (?), Justice, (?)
      Side B: 21B Bereson, Coostly, Mells
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1944 November 24 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 18A - Ward and Ormond conv 8.21 1+2 8.27
      Side B: 18B - Ormond and Ward 8.21 - 8.22
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A label reads: #19A Leeke - Lea 8.21 + 8.22 Conv 1 + 2 78
      Side B label reads: #19B Lea + Leeke 8.21-8.22 Conv 1 + 2 78
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: #3A - J8.21(2), J9.22, J9.22 Conv
      Side B: #3B - J10.25(1), J10.25(2), J11.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: J1.24, J1.25, J2.21, J2.22
      Side B: J3.20, J3.21, J4.16
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 2A - J5.31, 2 cuts
      Side B: 2B - J7.23, J7.24(1), J7.24(2), J8.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 3A - J8.21(2), J9.22, J9.22 com 2
      Side B: 3B - J10.25 com1, J10.25 .. 2, J11.21
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 1A - Hurtz, Griffith, Unit I
      Side B: 1B - Hendriek, Gill, Unit I
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 33A - J5.31 - Lt. Hobsore, Lt. R. Stolmson
      Side B: 33B - J5.31 - BR. S. Johnson, Lt. L.W. Hobson
    - Disc recording in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 14, 18, 19
      Side B: 15, 16, 17
    - Disc recording in Japanese and KLSU radio broadcast, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 9C - J5.31
      Side B: KLSU Stanford Scene
    - Disc recordings of Book I: Section II: 1-22, 1943 May 11 (Record cabinet)
      Book I: Section II: 1-22
      Hyojun Nihongo Tokumon
      Szuzaki-Tzumori
    - Disc recordings of Book I: Section II: 23-40, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Book I: Section II: 23-40
    - Douglas MacArthur speech, 194? July 25 (Record cabinet)
      MacArthur speaks on the birth of a new, independent nation. He is likely speaking about the Philippines, as he is introduced as "The Liberator of the Philippines," and he speaks about previous American military involvement with the country.
      Also on the original disc are two short excerpts of music.
    - East Asian radio transmissions, 194? December 24 (Record cabinet)
      This disc is a set of foreign broadcasts recorded from the air. The program is not in English, and the program sounds like it is in some East Asian language.
      The sound quality of the disc seems to indicate it itself is a copy of another disc.
      12/24 #2
      7:06-7:07
      7:16-7:22
      7:25-7:29
      Side B is unlabelled.
    - Japanese conversation drills, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: J8.21 Conv 2, J9.22 Conv 1, J9.22 Conv 2
      Side B: J10.25, J11.21
    - Japanese lesson sound recording unit 19, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Disc recording of a lesson in Japanese. Actors conduct two-person scenarios.
    - Japanese lesson sound recording unit 20, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Kato, Naki, Fujiyoshi, and Hamachi disc recording, 1945 May 18 (Record cabinet)
      1. Kato + Naki
      2. Kato + Fujiyoshi
      3. Fujiyoshi + Hamachi
    - Malayan and Thai broadcasts, 194? January 14 (Record cabinet)
      Radio broadcasts recorded off the airwaves.
      Side A: Sample of Malayan from Chungking 6:33-6:35, 7:02-7:12 Thai?
      Side B: 7-7:15 News Thai
    - National Broadcasting Company presents the San Francisco Radio Play House, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Newscasts, 1943 March 1-5 (Record cabinet)
      Recording of radio transmissions from the airwaves.
      Transcribed from the label on the discs
      Part 01: TITLE 6:01 - 6:09 6:09 - 6:15 #1 DATE 3/1/43
      Part 02: TITLE 6:16 - 6:29 #2 DATE 3/1/43
      Part 03: TITLE 6:14 - 6:27 #1 DATE 3/2
      Part 04: TITLE 6:25 - 6:31 #2 RECORDER 7:07 - 7:18 DATE 3/2
      Part 05: TITLE 6:09 - 6:23 #1 DATE 3/3
      Part 06: TITLE 6:23 - 6:32 #2 RECORDER 7:00 - 7:04 DATE 3/3
      Part 07: TITLE 6:06 - 6:18 #1 DATE 3/4/43
      Part 08: TITLE 6:19 - 6:30 #2 RECORDER 7:04 - 7:07 DATE 3/4/43
      Part 09: TITLE 6:08 - 6:21 #1 DATE 3/5
      Part 10: TITLE 6:21 - 6:32 #2 DATE 3/5
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China radio transmissions, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      Covers fighting in the Pacific Theater and China's foreign relationships with the West.
      The audio quality is less than expected. The disc appears to have been cut at a slower speed than 33 RPM. The pitch is likewise off.
    - Radio broadcasts, 194? January 5 (Record cabinet)
      1/5 #1
      6:06-6:31
      Writing on the original sleeve reads:
      4/1/43 #3
      This went on for a while afterward,
      but I didn't have any more room.
      I seriously doubt if all this is news.
      Writing on the other side of the original sleeve reads:
      3/16/43
    - Radio programs in Japanese, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: A studio-produced drama
      Part 2: Sports show
    - Radio programs in Japanese, 1946 June 24 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Man on the Street, number 14
      Part 2: Part of a drama in Japanese
    - Radio transmissions, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      1/2 number 1, number 2
    - Radio transmissions, 1943 April 14 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 6:13 - 6:15, 6:15 - 6:22, 6:27 - 6:35
      Side B: 6:35-6:37, 6:42-6:46, 6:50-6:57
    - Radio transmissions, 1943 March 3-8 (Record cabinet)
      Side A label in pencil reads: 7:07-7:15 #3 3/3/43
      Side A label in ink reads: 6:27-6:30 outside 3/8/43 #2
      Side B label reads: 6:14 - 6:26 #1 3/8/43
      Original sleeve side B label reads: 3/8/43 #1 #2 outside, reverse
    - Radio transmissions, 1943 April 14 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 7:02 - 7:15
      Side B: 7:15 - 7:27
      Original sleeve label reads: #'s 1 & 2, 4/14/43, it sounds as if they have changed the order of things. The reception was pretty bad in spots, but the gaps between are music. It was about 5 minutes of music + 5 of talking.
    - Radio transmissions, 194? March 10 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 6:07 - 6:20
      Side B: 6:21 - 6:34
    - Radio transmissions, 194? February 24 (Record cabinet)
      Radio transmissions recorded off the airwaves
      Side A: #3 - 6:11-6:25
      Side B: #4 - 6:25-6:32, 6:58-6:59, 7:07-7:12
    - Radio transmissions, 194? February 26 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: 5:56 - 5:59, 6:00 - 6:10
      Side B: 6:10 - 6:24
    - Radio transmissions, 194? February 27 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: #3 - 6:19-6:29, 6:30-6:32
      Side B: #4 - 7:02-7:05, 7:10-7:19
    - Radio transmissions, 194? February 27 (Record cabinet)
      5:49-5:58, 6:01-6:05, 6:05-6:18
    - Sound recording, 1943 March 16 and April 1 (Record cabinet)
      6:10-6:31 #1
      7:10-7:19 #2
      6:54-6:59
      7:08-7:18
    - Sound recording of the Japanese emperor announcing the surrender to the Japanese people, 1917 July 21 (Record cabinet)
      Both discs were originally in an outer sleeve with the label: "Sound recording of the Japanese emperor announcing surrender to the Japanese people, July 21, 1917??"
    - Sports Parade and test cuts sound recordings, 1946 (Record cabinet)
      The Mutual Broadcasting System program Sports Parade features a roundup of several sporting events occurring in the United States. Included are a fishing event, women's diving in San Francisco, and golfing for WWII veterans. Hosted by Stoney McGlynn in Philadelphia. The program is incomplete.
    - Thai radio broadcasts, 194? December 9 (Record cabinet)
      12/9
      6:05-6:30
      THAI BROADCAST
      12/9 #2
      inside
      7:02-7:12
      outside
      7:15-7:30
    - Tokyo Records disc 101, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Tokyo Records disc 102, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Tokyo Records disc 104, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Tokyo Records disc 110, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
    - Unidentified Asian radio broadcasts, 1943 March 2-9 (Record cabinet)
      Radio transmissions recorded from the airwaves.
      Side A label reads: 6:25- 6:32 #3 7:00 - 7:06 2/26
      Side B label reads: 6:42+6:44 6:50-6:51, 6:57-6:58 7:07-7:10 #4 7:11-7:12 2/26
      Original sleeve Side A label reads: AXV 3/2/43, the reception was terrible most of the time.
      Original sleeve Side B label reads: 3/9/43 #2 all except inside 2 6:42-6:44 6:50 - 6:51 6:57-6:58 7:07-7:09
      Inner two cuts on side B are crossed out.
    - Unidentified program, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      A studio-produced program in Japanese; features multiple voices and background, traditional Japanese music.
    - Unidentified radio broadcasts, 194? January 25 and February 15 (Record cabinet)
      The broadcasts are in an East Asian language.
      1/25 #1
      6:10-6:30
      2/15 #1
      6:26-6:32
    - Unidentified radio transmissions, 1942 December 19, 1943 March 21 (Record cabinet)
      12/19 #1
      6:05-6:29.5
      12/19 #2
      6:30-6:32
      7:03-7:16
      3/12/43 #3
      7:14-7:21
    - Unidentified radio transmissions, 194? December 30 (Record cabinet)
      12/30 #1
      6:07-6:30
    - Unidentified radio transmissions, 194? January 6 (Record cabinet)
      Note on the original sleeve label reads:
      The reception was so bad from 6 to 6:30 that there was no point in recording at all.
  - The rest of the sound recordings are not yet described.
- Transcripts (Box 1)
  Translations of transcripts of Chinese communist broadcasts from Yenan, China.